Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Writings and Speeches, 1912-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Open Files, 1912-1993 and undated
  - Manalo, Bella
    - 1985. Article. Concept Testing: Crystal Ball or Crap Shoot? Once Over Lightly, May (Box 34)
  - Mancini, Robert A.
    - 1984. Article. Case for Localizing National Media. Marketing and Media Decisions, May (Box 34)
  - Manning, Burt, (1-2 of 17 folders)
    - 1975. Article. Stimulus and Response (Box 34)
    - 1977. Speech. Video Disc? Video Tape? Video Bust? (Box 34)
    - 1978. Speech. Everything Changes But People (Box 34)
    - 1978. Speech. Illiteracy--The Communications Cancer (Box 34)
    - 1978. Speech. It's Not What You Say, It's What They Hear (2 versions) (Box 34)
    - 1978. Speech. JWT Creative Seminar (Box 34)
    - 1978. Speech. Speech to NYO Creative Dept. (Box 34)
    - 1978. Speech. Yes--But What Responses? (Box 34)
    - 1979. Speech. Advertising Research--Stimulant or Depressant (Box 34)
    - 1979. Other writing. Messages from Manning (Wall Street Journal ad) (Box 34)
    - 1980. Speech. Speech in Manila on U.S. Advertising (Box 34)
    - 1980. Speech. Speech to JWT Atlanta Office (Box 34)
    - Circa 1980. Speech. Trends in U.S. Advertising (Box 34)
    - 1980. Speech. What Advertising Must Do in an Age of Suspicion (speech and article) (Box 34)
  - Manning, Burt (continued), (3-9 of 17 folders) (Box 35)
    - 1981. Speech. HVIE presentation to Board of Directors (Box 35)
    - 1981. Speech. Radio: Friendly Persuasion (Box 35)
    - 1982. Article. Bankers are Entitled to Their Money's Worth (Box 35)
    - 1982. Speech. Brand Personality (Box 35)
    - 1982. Other writing. Burt Manning on the Fine Art of Print (summary) (Box 35)
    - 1982. Speech. How Much is Great Advertising Worth? (Box 35)
    - 1982. Speech. In Defense of the Press (Box 35)
    - 1982. Speech. Is Advertising Dead? (Box 35)
    - 1982. Speech. Most Expensive Advertising in the World (Box 35)
    - 1982. Speech. Strategy: Semper Fideles (Box 35)
    - 1982-1983. Speech. How Advertising Works (2 versions) (Box 35)
    - 1982-1983. Speech. Roots of Communication (Box 35)
    - 1982-1991. Other writing. Memoranda and miscellaneous (Box 35)
    - 1983. Speech. Adweek Conference (Box 35)
    - 1983. Speech. How Understanding Attitudes Helps Us Judge Advertising (Box 35)
    - 1983. Speech. Speech to the Adweek Conference (Box 35)
    - 1983. Speech. Why Would Anybody Want to be in the Advertising Business? (Box 35)
    - 1984. Speech. Global Advertising: Fact or Fiction? (Box 35)
    - 1984. Speech. Pittsburgh Ad Club presentation (draft) (Box 35)
    - 1984. Speech. Standing Out in the Crowd (Box 35)
    - 1984. Speech. Unfulfilled Opportunities in Cable (Box 35)
    - 1984. Speech. Visual Revolution (2 versions) (Box 35)
    - 1985. Speech. Atlanta Ad Club (2 versions) (Box 35)
    - 1985. Speech. GTE Advertising Conference (Box 35)
    - 1985. Speech. Last Speech about Creativity You'll Ever need to Hear (Box 35)
    - 1985. Speech. What Chicago Did to Advertising (Box 35)
  - Manning, Burt (continued), (10-17 of 17 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1986. Speech. Visual Revolution (Box 36)
    - 1987. Speech. Thoughts on Timotei (Box 36)
    - 1988. Speech. Big Ideas: How to Make Them; How to Know Them; How to Keep Them Alive (Box 36)
    - 1988. Speech. Soul of a Company (Box 36)
    - 1989. Speech. Media: The New Creative Frontier? (Box 36)
    - 1994. Article. Advertising's Future: TV or not TV? The Advertiser, Fall (Box 36)
    - 1994. Speech. History of Kodak Brand Advertising (AAF World Series of Advertising) (Box 36)
    - 1995. Speech. Creating Maximum Bandwidth (World Federation of Advertisers Congress) (Box 36)
    - 1995. Speech. Presentation to American Business Publishers (Box 36)
    - Undated. Speech. Advertising that Moves Products (Box 36)
    - Undated. Speech. Last Sure-Fire Guaranteed Secret to Success in the Advertising Business (Box 36)
    - Undated. Speech. Our Creative Disciplines (Box 36)
    - Undated. Speech. Stimulus and Response (Box 36)
  - Marcus, Cubby
    - 1986. Article. TV Ads Are Getting Better Because Clients Are Getting Younger (Box 36)
  - Marcus, Dorothy
    - 1991. Speech. PR Person in Information Loop (Box 36)
  - Martrell, Charles
    - 1980. Speech. Speech to South American Quaker Managers (Box 36)
  - Massaro, Frank
    - 1984. Article. In the Picture. Television/Radio Age, May 28 (Box 36)
  - Matthews, Jack
    - 1978. Speech. How to Get More Business--Faster (Box 36)
  - Maxwell, Hamish
    - 1989. Speech. Remarks to Advertising Research Foundation (Box 36)
  - McCullough, Richard
    - 1980. Speech. Managing the New Media and the New Consumer: Implications for Food Advertising Strategy in 1990 (Box 36)
    - 1981. Speech. New Consumer and the Media: Implications for Meat Marketing Strategy for the 1980s (Box 36)
  - McKennan, William C.
    - 1935. Speech. Advertising Opportunities in the Federal Housing Program (Box 36)
    - 1937. Speech. Sales Conferences (Box 36)
    - 1953. Speech. How Advertising Can Best Create the Right Impression of You and the Industry (Box 36)
    - 1954. Speech. Speech to American Gas and Electric Service Corp. (Box 36)
    - 1954. Speech. Speech to Conference of Business and Industry (Box 36)
    - Circa 1955. Article. Challenge to American Enterprise (Box 36)
  - McMahon, Joseph M.
    - 1971. Speech. National Beer Wholesalers' Association Convention (Box 36)
  - McMurtry, Roy
    - 1977. Speech. Speech to Rotary Club (Box 36)
  - McNair, W. A.
    - 1947. Article. Statistics in Market Surveys (Box 36)
    - 1948. Article. Bedevilled with Detail (Box 36)
    - 1948. Speech. Market Research (Box 36)
  - McQuigg, John L.
    - 1961. Speech. Reducing Economic Illiteracy (Box 36)
  - Meads, Chip
    - 1966. Speech. 10 Creative Commandments for Young Account Representatives (Box 36)
    - 1966. Speech. Untitled (Box 36)
  - Meek, Samuel W.
    - Circa 1949. Article. La Colocacion de Productos Estranjeros en Estados Unidos (Box 36)
    - 1950. Article. American Market for European Goods (Box 36)
    - Circa 1950. Other writing. Die Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika (pamphlet) (Box 36)
    - 1950. Article. El Mercado Norteamericano para Articulos do Ultramar (Box 36)
  - Meffert, H.
    - 1980. Speech. Trends fur die Wege zum Verbraucher von Morgen (Box 36)
  - Melchers, Dan
    - 1990. Speech. Quebec Consumer (Box 36)
  - Metter, Bert
    - 1982. Article. Maestro Metter. JWT News, Fall (Box 36)
    - 1985. Article. Bert Metter of J. Walter Thompson on the New-Business Climate (Box 36)
    - 1985. Article. First Ad I Never Wrote (Mustang). Magazine Age, Jan. (Box 36)
    - 1985. Article. If He Zigs, You Zag if You Want to Stand Out. Back Stage, Dec. 20 (Box 36)
    - Undated. Article. Future of Advertising: Some Sure Things (Box 36)
  - Miller, Anthony G.
    - 1992. Speech. Idea Company (Box 36)
  - Miller, Thomas
    - 1995. Speech. 21st Century Consumers (Box 36)
  - Mills, Peter
    - 1984. Speech. Battle of the Burgers (Box 36)
  - Mims, Stewart L. (Box 37)
    - 1929. Speech. Les Demandes du Présent du Travail de Publicité (Box 37)
    - 1929. Speech. Strange Interlude of Advertising--The Actual Day's Work (Box 37)
    - Undated. Speech. Advertising Agency of the Future (Box 37)
  - Minto, Clive
    - 1978. Speech. Perspective on Client and Agency Relationships (Box 37)
  - Mitchell, Wesley C.
    - 1912. Other writing. Backward Art of Spending Money (booklet) (Box 37)
  - Monsarrat, John, (3 folders)
    - 1968. Article. Professionalism in Advertising Agency Practice (Box 37)
    - 1969. Speech. Why Advertising Isn't as Productive as Agencies and Clients Know How to Make It (Box 37)
    - 1971. Other writing. Case for the Full Service Agency (pamphlet, 2 versions) (Box 37)
    - 1971. Speech. Piecemealism: Footnotes from a Friendly Observation Post (Box 37)
    - 1985. Other writing. Angel on the Yardarm: The Beginnings of Fleet Radar Defense and the Kamikaze Threat (monograph) (Box 37)
    - 1992. Other writing. Addendum to the Archives (memoir) (Box 37)
  - Moon, Tony
    - 1977. Article. Straight from the Horse's Mouth. JWT News, Aug. (Box 37)
  - Morch, Sys
    - 1973. Speech. Speculations Based on Current Sociologican and Toiletries Marketing Trends (Box 37)
    - 1975. Speech. Review of Fashions in the United States in 1974 and for 1975 (Box 37)
    - 1975. Speech. Sociological Trends in the United States in 1973 and 1974 (Box 37)
  - Moskowitz, Milton
    - 1966. Article. India Editorial (Box 37)
    - Undated. Article. Business and Society, 5 issues (Box 37)
  - Munger, N. Terry
    - 1968. Other writing. Some Important Things I Believe a Young Account Representative Should Know About Library Research (pamphlet, with Elizabeth L. Smith and Marilyn Modern Bockman) (Box 37)
    - 1980. Other writing. What Every Account Representative Should Know About Library Research (pamphlet, with Elizabeth L. Smith) (Box 37)
  - Murphy, David
    - 1977. Article. Media Professionals. Television/Radio Age, June 20 (Box 37)
  - Murray, Jane Ellen
    - 1974. Article. Freedom of Choice is Best Consumer Weapon. Advertising Age, June 3 (Box 37)
    - 1975. Article. Savvy Marketers Will Improve Women's Ad Roles. Advertising Age, Mar. 3 (Box 37)
    - 1978. Article. Would Your Daughter Want to Marry This Ad? Advertising Age, Aug. 7 (Box 37)
    - 1979. Other writing. Draft of essay on Chicago Office history (Box 37)
  - Naegele, R.E.
    - 1979. Other writing. Statement on price controls in Canada (Box 37)
  - Naisbitt, John
    - Circa 1980. Speech. Untitled (Box 37)
  - Naples, Michael
    - 1977. Speech. Successful New Products (Box 37)
  - Nelson, Elizabeth
    - 1977. Other writing. Consumer Change and Conflict (draft of conference paper) (Box 37)
  - Nelson, Linnea
    - 1942. Article. Timebuyer Thinks of Radio Selling and Wonders Why There Aren't More Department Stores on the Air. Broadcasting, May 4 (Box 37)
    - 1943. Article. Few War Casualties: Early Fears Not Justified. Variety, July (Box 37)
    - 1944. Speech. Why Radio Time Buying is Hell (Box 37)
    - 1945. Article. How Time Buyers View Broadcast Measurement Bureau... (editorial). The Advertiser, Apr. (Box 37)
    - 1949. Article. How Should Television be Sold? (article quotes Nelson) (Box 37)
  - Newman, Blaise
    - 1983. Speech. Retail Advertising Seminar (Box 37)
  - Nichols, David
    - 1979. Speech. Consumer: Rules Have Changed (Box 37)
  - Novotny, John
    - 1975. Article. Smaller Countries Lead in Fee Use. Advertising Age, June 2 (Box 37)
  - Oakley, Harry
    - 1981-1986. Other writing. Memoranda and miscellaneous (Box 37)
  - O'Brien, Walter J. (Wally), (4 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1981. Speech. Future's Not What It Used To Be! (Box 38)
    - 1981. Speech. Managing Change--The Role of Communications (Box 38)
    - 1981. Speech. Speech to JWT personnel (Box 38)
    - 1983. Other writing. Memoranda and miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - 1983. Speech. Presentation to NYO (Box 38)
    - 1984. Speech. Introduction to Epcot Meeting (Box 38)
    - 1984. Article. Realities of Global Marketing. Advertising Age, Dec. 10 (Box 38)
    - 1986. Speech. Worldwide Management Trends (Box 38)
  - O'Donnell, Joseph, (2 folders)
    - 1984. Speech. Expectations of Our People (Box 38)
    - 1986. Other writing. Memoranda and miscellaneous (Box 38)
  - Oldland, John
    - 1981. Speech. Lifestyle Changes in the 1980s (Box 38)
  - Olins, Wally
    - 1980. Speech. I'm a Little Worried About Marketing (Box 38)
  - Olsen, G. Douglas
    - 1993. Other writing. Sounds of Silence: Functions and Use of Silence in Television Advertising (academic essay) (Box 38)
  - Olson, Sid
    - Undated. Speech. Four Freedoms of Advertising (written for Lee Iacocca for AAAA Meeting; annotated "best thing ever written about agency-client relations") (Box 38)
  - O'Meara, Walter
    - 1948. Other writing. Brink of Madness (fiction). Saturday Evening Post, May 8 (Box 38)
    - 1948. Speech. New York Advertising Man Goes West (Box 38)
  - Ostrofe, Allen F.
    - 1972. Article. Communications and the Art of Living in a Cybernated Age (Box 38)
  - O'Toole, John
    - 1979. Other writing. Organization (memorandum) (Box 38)
  - Owett, Bernard, (5 folders)
    - 1972. Speech. Talk given to graduate class in Art-Design (Box 38)
    - 1973. Speech. Listerine Advertising--talk given at Harvard Business School (Box 38)
    - 1974. Speech. Listerine Story (Box 38)
    - 1974. Speech. Talk on Designing Effective Advertising (Box 38)
    - Circa 1974. Speech. TV Ad (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. General Talk on Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. It's Not What You Do, It's the Way You Do It (Box 38)
    - 1975. Article. Owett on Film. JWT News, Mar. (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. Popular Culture in the U.S.A. How Does it Affect Advertising? (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. Slice of Whose Life (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. Talk on Advertising in 1975 (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. Talk on Commercial Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1975. Speech. Talk on Print Advertising (Box 38)
    - Circa 1975. Speech. Talk on Successful Salesmanship (Box 38)
    - 1976. Speech. How to Become Rich and Famous through Graphic Design (Box 38)
    - 1976. Speech. TV Ad (Box 38)
    - 1978. Speech. Listerine Antiseptic (Box 38)
    - 1978. Speech. Talk on Radio (Box 38)
    - 1978. Article. TV Ad: Some of My Best Friends are Continuing Characters (Box 38)
    - 1978. Speech. Why Use a Continuing Character (Box 38)
    - 1979. Speech. Talk on Commercials--IBM Presentation (Box 38)
    - 1979. Speech. Talk on Importance of Production and Execution in Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1980. Speech. Changing Lifestyles Means Changing Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1980. Speech. Changing Lifestyle Means changing Advertising in the '80s (Box 38)
    - 1980. Article. Commercials reflect changing life styles (editorial) (Box 38)
    - 1980. Article. JWT's Owett Talk on Changing Lifestyles (Box 38)
    - 1980. Speech. Next Fifty Years, a Fearless Forecast (Box 38)
    - 1980. Speech. Red, White and Blue in :30 and :60 (Box 38)
    - 1980. Speech. Very Good Season for Dummies (Box 38)
    - 1981. Speech. Burger King Story (Box 38)
    - 1981. Speech. Changing Lifestyles: How Do They Affect Advertising? (Box 38)
    - 1982. Speech. Fine Art of Survival (Box 38)
    - 1982. Speech. Ingredients for Successful Communication (Box 38)
    - 1982. Article. Second Generation (Box 38)
    - 1983. Speech. Advertising Execution in the '80s Where is it Moving and Why (Box 38)
    - 1983. Speech. OTC Advertising in the U.S.A. Today (Box 38)
    - 1983. Speech. Talk on Effective Production in Warner Lambert Commercials (Box 38)
    - 1983. Speech. Talk on OTC Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1984. Speech. More than You'll Ever Need to Know about Television Production (Box 38)
    - 1984. Speech. Warner Lambert International (Box 38)
    - 1988. Speech. Use and Abuse of Creative Trends in Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1989. Speech. Commercials! Where Do Those Damned Ideas Come From? (Box 38)
    - 1989. Speech. How to Create Effective Packaged Goods Advertising in the 1990's (Box 38)
    - 1989. Speech. Talk on Rock and Roll (Box 38)
    - 1990. Speech. Anticipating the Nineties: A Look at Things that Will Influence Advertising during the Next Ten Years (Box 38)
    - 1990. Speech. Talk on the Past and the Future of Advertising (Box 38)
    - Undated. Speech. Ad-Man at the Movies (Box 38)
    - Undated. Article. ...And the Rockets' Red Glare, the Ads Bursting in Air... (Box 38)
    - Undated. Other writing. Interview of B. Owett regarding the 56th Annual Art Directors Show (Box 38)
  - Palmer, W. G.
    - 1937. Speech. New Frontier for Advertising (Box 38)
  - Parker, Austin
    - 1973. Speech. Marketing in Mexico (Box 38)
  - Parker, Ward, (1 of 2 folders)
    - 1957. Speech. Merchandising--The Vital 50% of the Advertising Job (Box 38)
    - 1959. Speech. Agency's Function in Today's Marketing Concept (Box 38)
    - 1959. Speech. Agency Views Space Management (Box 38)
    - 1959. Speech. Is Agency-Producer Cooperation Possible? (2 versions) (Box 38)
    - 1960. Speech. How Has JWT Equipped Itself to Meet its Marketing Responsibilities in the '60s (Box 38)
    - 1960. Speech. Marketing Counsel or Specialists in Advertising (Box 38)
    - 1960. Speech. Place of Premiums in Marketing Strategy (Box 38)
    - 1961. Speech. Retail Revolution and its Significance to National Advertisers (Box 38)
    - 1961. Speech. Revolution in Retailing (Box 38)
  - Parker, Ward (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1962. Speech. Retail Revolution and its Significance to Marketing Executives (Box 39)
    - 1962. Speech. Your Role in the Retailing Revolution (Box 39)
    - 1963. Speech. Merits and Tie-Ins from the Standpoint of Creativity and Coordination (Box 39)
  - Patterson, Jim
    - 1990. Speech. J. Walter Thompson Company's Approach to Creative Advertising (Box 39)
  - Pavão, Leonel (Lee), (2 folders)
    - 1983. Article. What's Brewing in Brazil. JWT News, May. (Box 39)
    - Circa 1984. Speech. How Does an Increased Commitment to Global or Regional Advertising Campaigns Affect Local Creative Department? (Box 39)
  - Payton, Bob
    - 1980s. Article. Bob Payton Tour to London Guide (Box 39)
  - Pearson, George
    - Circa 1937. Speech. Future Magazine of Advertising (Box 39)
  - Pearson, Mary
    - 1979. Other writing. Second Time Around (report on Canadian women in the workforce) (Box 39)
  - Pedersen, Sigrid H.
    - 1970. Speech. Advertising Agency Role in the Selection and Use of Trademarks (Box 39)
  - Peller, Burt
    - 1975. Speech. Focus on Research Creditability (Box 39)
    - 1976. Other writing. Reaching the U.S. Businessman (draft) (Box 39)
    - 1979. Speech. Measurement in Business Media Research (Box 39)
    - 1984. Article. Media Strategies for the Information Age. Marketing and Media Decisions, special issue, Apr. (Box 39)
  - Pershad, Deepak
    - 1981. Article. Pay TV. Stimulus, Sept. (Box 39)
  - Peters, Jack
    - 1985. Other writing. Memoranda and miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - Peterson, Esther
    - 1984. Speech. Remarks before World Trade Conference (Box 39)
  - Pfaff, Waren
    - 1970. Speech. Flying Leap (Box 39)
  - Phillips, Anne
    - 1975. Speech. Greenhouse: Making Music for Advertising (Box 39)
  - Phillips, Dorothy M.
    - 1973. Article. Dialog, and Marketing Research (Box 39)
  - Pierce, Thurman R., JR.
    - 1973. Speech. How Newspaper Promotion Men and Women Can Better Serve Their National Clients and Advertising Agencies (Box 39)
    - 1974. Speech. How an Advertising Agency Works (AAAA presentation with Larry Sachnowitz and Jeremy Sprague) (Box 39)
    - 1975. Other writing. Outlook for Newspapers over the Next Decade (draft) (Box 39)
    - 1975. Article. Technology, Solid Finances Bolster Newspapers. Advertising Age, Nov. 17 (Box 39)
    - 1976. Speech. Remarks at INAE convention (Box 39)
    - 1977. Speech. Remarks at ANPA Research Institute (Box 39)
    - 1979. Article. 8 Out of 10 Newspapers. Marketing and Media Decisions, Aug. (Box 39)
    - 1979. Speech. Remarks at Newspaper Graphics Seminar (Box 39)
    - 1983. Article. New Values in Print. Marketing and Media Decisions, Mar. (Box 39)
    - 1984. Speech. Newspaper's Number One Position in the Advertising Market: Can They Hold Onto It? (Box 39)
  - Pittman, Bob
    - 1985. Speech. Greenbrier talk (Box 39)
  - Poletti, Jean Ellis
    - 1955. Article. Politics Begin at the Polls (Box 39)
  - Pollan, Jim (?)
    - 1985. Speech. Atlanta Analysts Meeting (Box 39)
  - Porter, Arthur A., (2 folders)
    - 1955. Speech. How Much Can the Consumer Take? (Box 39)
    - 1955. Speech. Let's Try for That Extra 10% (Box 39)
    - 1956. Speech. Dynamic Media Strategy (Box 39)
    - 1956. Speech. Dynamic Media Strategy in Businesspaper Advertising (Box 39)
    - 1956. Article. Four Top Agencies and Their Media (Box 39)
    - 1956. Speech. Some Things I Would Be Thinking about If I Were a Newspaper Publisher (Box 39)
    - 1957. Speech. Advertising Problem (Box 39)
    - 1957. Speech. Cash in on Color (Box 39)
    - 1957. Speech. How Competitive Can You Get (Box 39)
    - 1957. Article. Mediaview (Box 39)
    - 1957. Speech. New Dimension of Radio (Box 39)
    - 1957. Speech. Third Dimension in Media Values (Box 39)
    - 1959. Speech. Look Forward to the 1960s (Box 39)
  - Powell, Hugo
    - 1993. Speech. Introductory remarks to Canadian Advertising Congress (Box 39)
  - Powers, Frank E.
    - 1954. Article. There is Nothing Too Little... (Box 39)
    - 1955. Speech. Craftsmanship and the Type Director (Box 39)
    - 1955. Speech. Let's Make It Easy to Read! (Box 39)
    - Circa 1961. Article. Tips on Type (Box 39)
    - Undated. Speech. Why the Dual Standards in Typography? (Box 39)
  - Pratt, Lee
    - 1973-1983. Other writing. Miscellaneous small. Article. s and clippings (Box 39)
  - Preschel, W. Lee, (3 folders)
    - 1974. Other writing. Project for JWT Central America 1974 (draft for booklet) (Box 39)
    - 1983. Speech. Ten Tried and Trusted Methods of Getting the Least from Your Advertising Agency (Box 39)
  - Preston, Marion
    - 1975. Other writing. Quoted in article (Box 39)
    - 1978. Article. Sitting Down to Talk: Advertising World and Performers' Unions. Broadcasting, Jan. 9 (Box 39)
  - Priday, Paul
    - 1984. Speech. Brand Culture (Box 39)
  - Pritchard, Jane
    - 1995. Speech. Can Your Agency Walk and Chew Gum at the Same Time? (Box 39)
  - Proulx, Monique
    - 1978. Other writing. Five Million Women: A Study of the Canadian Housewife (report) (Box 39)
  - Quelch, John A.
    - 1994. Speech. Private Label 1994 (Box 39)
  - Rago, Rosalinde
    - 1985. Article. Turning on the Light…The Synetics Approach. Once Over Lightly, July (Box 39)
  - Ralston, Richard
    - Circa 1965. Other writing. Quest for Silence (essay) (Box 39)
  - Raymond, Charles E., (3 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1925. Article. My Forty Years in the Advertising Business (Box 40)
    - 1932. Other writing. Reminiscences (Box 40)
    - Circa 1935. Other writing. History of JWT (Box 40)
  - Reed, Vergil D., (1-7 of 11 folders)
    - Circa 1931. Article. Advertising on a Small Appropriation (Box 40)
    - 1933. Speech. Stop the Retail Sales Tax (Box 40)
    - 1941. Article. Data Now Available on How Distribution Met Depression (Box 40)
    - 1943. Article. Less Selling But More Marketing (Box 40)
    - 1943. Article. War-Time Facts for Industry (Box 40)
    - 1944. Speech. Government De-Control (Box 40)
    - 1944. Article. Look at What They Found in the Trash Cans! (Box 40)
    - 1944. Article. Now is the Time for Government Agencies to Release Marketing Data (Box 40)
    - 1944. Article. War Time Facts and Peace Time Needs (Box 40)
    - 1944. Speech. Where are They and Where Will They Be? (speech and article) (Box 40)
    - 1945. Speech. Population and Purchasing Power (speech and article, 3 versions) (Box 40)
    - 1945. Other writing. Post-War Economic Policy and Planning (U.S. House of Representatives Report, Reed's personal copy) (Box 40)
    - 1945. Article. Re-Establishing Markets for Packaged and Branded Merchandise (Box 40)
    - 1946. Article. If Dreams Were Firm Orders, We Would Never Need Salesmen Again (Box 40)
    - 1946. Speech. Market Outlook for the Construction Industry (Box 40)
    - 1946. Speech. Market Research (Box 40)
    - 1946. Speech. Marketing Research Has Gone Upstairs (Box 40)
    - 1946. Article. Markets Change Faster than You Think (Box 40)
    - 1946. Speech. Promotion and Research (Box 40)
    - 1946. Article. Reading America's Palm (Box 40)
    - 1946. Article. Trends in Population and Purchasing Power (Box 40)
    - 1946. Article. You are One of These (Box 40)
    - 1947. Article. Base on Which Selling Plans and Policies Must Build (Box 40)
    - 1947. Article. Book Review (Box 40)